...at least you wait you wake up.
However, jan.
My name is...guiding and today will talk about up
...and how to?
Use up insight for the diagnostic purposes I hope you having a great
shall I certainly enjoy all
the innovations that we presented this week and today we'll talk about the up
...which is yet another service that we release in
public preview which means that you all can go and start using it?
First of all it is important to evaluate this presentation
we welcome your feedback it is important...
Now better okay thank you.
please evaluate...thistalk and you can start with...mike problems.
I will be talking about ...insight.
And, how to use it to troubleshooting diagnose your servicehow many of you have seen
previous stock which was like a half an hour an hour earlier by dale
...ok so I'll try to minimize
the overlap and I think my job will be two-d mystified what up insight how up
...is actually working and that's what I will spend most of my time today?
Running a successful app is hard.
And, we believe that every business these days is a software business I have a scale
thatsends the might wait up into the cloud...can track whether
I'm improving mike api or declining and, in many cases success
...the businesses directly related to the successor fehler we software and unless you
can measure it you can't control it requirements...changing
computation is stiff is very important for you to actually know what's going on I
would break these scenarios of knowing what's going on into
two fundamentally different buckets one is I would say find fix release
where we're trying to maintain the health of our service
and another bucket is usage knowing your users how you
...engage with the application that I would say bucket like build measure
learning today specifically I'll be focusing mostly
...find fix release type of scenarios where you need to
instrumented application for a trouble shoot to
the simplify troubleshooting purposes.
You running business and you have pra you have lots of questions.
Whether my application is up or down and I would say that
those are availability questions whether
I'm failing with certain requests and if the amount
of failures number of failures exceeding certain threshold and I need to jump
...start fixing my site you also have...performance
questions and performance questions I would put into two different buckets one is.
Responsiveness of your obligation which means that what
This is you hear me okay good so this is a more
than at a job methodology I would say and this is not a any particular
tool this is a culture
...and the collaboration between development and
operations while we look at this collaboration there are lots of friction points,
for example, when you releases application and production
sometimes you don't know what's going on there how many customers are accessing particular feature
...applications up and running when you known?
Based on a twitter feed that...application is down sometimes it's not enough
the data that you have is not enough to reproduce the issue and
the fix the problem and the type of systems that
developers and operations use don't talk
to each other and then once you prioritize issues on
war when you trying to understand the impact of an issue
sometimes you don't have information whether I need to fix this particular issue or that
because you don't know the impact you don't know-how many users actually have been affected by
this particular fehler versus in other how many of you running production
sites awesome do have in your organizations the notion of ls
...light site incident type process where you have
...call in the middle-of-the-night and you have a bridge and people
wake up and ok so few of you.
That's where the rule.
Keeps me on my...that's where these type of for tooling
in this type of information is very important because typically the process works like this you have
a issue potentially automatically detected by you
or monitoring system and therule of thumb eighty percent of
issues should be automatically detected and,
the rest twenty issues is pretty much based on
the user feedback or somebody in the not browsing and suddenly seeing some
anomalies so when the issues detected then there is a triage process happening where you
need to identify whether this is a real problem that you
need to investigate or this is a bug thatcan be
fix later and this early triage significantly
impact the cost you either wake-up people in the middle-of-the-night and people are under the
gun or you basically creates fthree incident and
their managers at their leisure decide how to prioritize that particular bug
versus some other backlog items so it is very important to provide a
...comprehensive wvu on your telemetry
to speedup meantime
to detect meantime and meantime to resolve?
Or mitigate now what is up...
Up...is a application plays an application performance management space
so we collect telemetry from all applications out there and
devices so whether it's you have ios and lloyd windows phone
or...applications whether it's a dot net java
each be python node you name it we collect
all the telemetry we send that telemetry into the cloud.
Within reach that telemetry and,
...slice and dice we create indexes of that telemetry and then we provide powerful
inside so you cananalyze your telemetry over the web the point I want to make and I will
be keep reiterating this point over and over because we had lots and lots of questions
...and site.
Works for any application running anywhere whether
it'samazon cloud google cloud as a cloud on
...public you name it works.
The analytical ux user experience is part of
...so, you need to login to adjective view the data however
your application can run anywhere now if you look at what up in...consist
off if you think about applications the way we treat application,
application is an essentially
a bucket of telemetry uniquely identify by ip?
And, what we are doing with this bucket of telemetry we send to you
can send telemetry their first of all you can look at your front-end application
...you-can ping it from outside and we have eighteen points
a presence around the globe that you canexecute
...paying if you familiar with let's say keynote...as
setting them that would be the similar scenario what we do however
re-execute not just simple thing we execute the
visual studio web tests so you can record multi-step transactions?
And, run it from multiple...presence in this case
you can detect not only that your site is up or down but also you
could detect that you have you resources are up, for example,
you can record a simple let's say you have a calmer site and you have a search you
can record...session that does the typical search.
And, if you get the results back, you know, for a fact that actually this search
you all your search subsystem is up so we do not recommend to record
web test for every possible use case scenario instead
...critical scenarios that validate resource availability and
that's how you can test that your site not only are but all your
important resources pieces of technologies are up however it does not.
Replace the real user monitoring and we monitor
real users from the client-side where you can
...install...sdk on the ios device android device windows
phone device or you can add are javascript snippet into your browser
which will give you the actual responsiveness and performance
all of your end-users we also monitor it from the
server-side where we can detect failures before
...degradation and when we detect those performance degradation if you think what a server
application does when it runs when it receives the request it relies
on external services let's say I can call the sequel database
right I can call I can query blob storage ki can rely on some other
...cf services so forth so we would
automatically monitor that andwe would correlate all that technology
together and that's later on that something that I will show you and,
the last but not least is the infrastructure so,
we've talked about clients we've talked about the server the you application code that's
running on the server and then you run on the actual boxer
...a doctor and in many cases you need to know the health of
that box itself especially if you running on
param high-density environment where multiple let's say websites are sharing
the same machine you want to know about the cpu memory io thread
starvation so forth we collect that as well so what I'm going to do right now I'm
going to quickly show you how we do that?
To do so I'm going to start with visual studio.
And, I will go quickly through a similar
flow that dale showed but I will talk a little bit more what are we
doing behind-the-scene so what I'm going to do is I'm going to
create a web project.
And, let's.
Let's call it the.
Build demo.
One-two-three just to make sure that I want clash with anybody.
I also want to do one more thing I
want to create a resource group how many of you have heard about resource group.
Awesome so resource group is...hosting containment relationship where I can
creator resource group and then put multiple resources into that resource group currently
imagine resource do gives you three.
Value-added it gives you it's a single point of
our back so if you create a resource group for your staging
versus production you can said different permissions for your staging resources versus production
resources that's one second you can see billing for
that resource group and you'll be able to see how much you pay for your staging resources
versus production resources and third all the issues all the alerts
will be aggregated on the level of resource group so by looking at the resource group you
can kind of cc toll and I don't know-how many of you have
seen gallery as...gallery.
The sorry customization for blades through the gallery okay...
show you that because that's very cool feature that apparently not many people have seen and,
what I'm going to do is I'm going to create this resource group with my application
and in this particular case I will host ...to be...will hosted and measure?
I'll pick my a
prototype subscription I'll pick my region.
And, while visual studios going through motions let me explain what will just
what will happenfirst of all we will create a resource group called
...demo one-two-three second will create up insight resource called
...demo one-two-three and...place it into that resource group third
will create web site called...one-two-three I didn't check that and
put it into the into that resource group so what I would expect is that at the end
...have resource group with two resources in it up insight and the
website ok now also what you see here is hopefully
we'll get will cooperate with me the visual studio.
Will upload all the
new get packages to my machine so, I'll get latest and greatest?
New gets from the from the web.
Also we it will create up...
configure which basically contains configuration for
application and site and it will put their application
...id...we call it instrumentation key into that up and
...and it looks like it's there so let me run it and then we'll
talk what how we've collected all these telemetry so I want?
And, actually even event this way.
Is the points I want to make...here?
So, what I want you to notice that every time when I click there
is something happening in the output window and right now we're in debug
mode and let me talk about a little bit about what's happening in visual studio at this time?
Posit first of all you notice that there is a toast and this toast would allow me
to jump into...as a portal to see telemetry that we
just collected also I want to point out that we are showing
you the telemetry that we are collecting right now and as you've seen that
...in the debug mode in visual studio we...to limit tree out...magically like
the automatically every time when I click there's something going into the wire
in production settings that's not feasible so we have a
mechanism to batch it and we send it every thirty seconds.
So, that is done for you automatically now as you see as part of this telemetry
we collect lots of information and let me talk a little bit about how
...is actually...first of all we have what we call.
Up and site core which is a essentially shame over rj
song and point public endpoint and this low-level api
...us number of functions
of functions that define our domain model earlier I
was talking about the notion of application which is essentially a bucket and this guy bucket of telemetry
this guy and we believe that application accepts request it spits
out exceptions and the traces and logs it also
can be instrumented for usage events over control flow events and metrics and it
relies on dependencies and coincidentally we have
api surface that covers exactly that we have truck exception track metric
track request drug dependency...page views so forth so our core is
decayed provides that.
On top of that we have logging framework so if you guys
already instrumented applications with some kind of instrumentation so how many of
you've already instrumented apps with let's say log format...log.
Awesome so if...already instrumented your application
withsome code we want to preserve that instrumentation and we want to
operation allies it so we have our
own listeners a pander subscribers you name it for
most popular logging framework and what you can do is you can basically
channel your logging information up into the cloud and you'll get to
benefits with that we will first of all provide a ui
user experience that would allow you to slice and dice information and very
often I've seen with instrumentation framework implementation people dumping to do
...and then duty sequel to minute so?
We do much better than that we have a full-blown you why analytical you why that would
allow you to understand what's going on in your log but we also correlate
those logs with our request so you'd be able to see that while processing this particular
request these this is the telemetry that was
that this request was ...processing so that's our second layer
soft-core logging and the third layer is our
automatic where without you writing any line of code we
would collect data as you've seen what I just...by virtue of
meet checking well, keeping that check box for web applications we are a meeting
...elementary and I'll show you that telemetry in a second but that's...
That's our to instrumentation layer and it consists of two pieces first of all
...to a standard let's say requests or
we collect automatically exceptions but we also collect standard properties and if
you look here I don't know if it is well, it's.
You can see this but...we're collecting windows version
we're collecting device model we collect a lot ofip address obviously so forth we
collect out-of-the-box a lot of properties that you would need for...
troubleshooting analytical purposes ok nowlet me go into the.
Into my application in.
To look at the data that we've sent.
So, what I did I just click on a deeply...and?
Hopefully what you'll see is you will see the.
For...demo one-two-three.
Okay, so, I clicked and, this is my browser data.
So, again,
this is we've done we've collected all this data with no...no.
...instrumentation...
Now what I'd like to do is I'd like to.
...little bit and I'll show you.
The typical typical before I do I
promised to show you how we've where's the magic and
...is here we added...a cv module.
Okay,
so, we can collect all the traffic that's going in and out.
From your website ok that's how we attach to all
your request processing if you need to attached to the tracing
what you can do is let's say you using system that diagnostics you can go to manage
know get packages.
And, if you look at the application.
Insights listener you would be able to see essentially
...clip trace listener you'll be able to see other the up...so there is
...log...format you'd be able to
the see all those the trace listeners and the only thing you have to do is add that trace
listener to your application and we will do everything for you we would put our trace listener as
...let's say in a pander in the configuration or a listener in the configuration for
...system diagnostics okay and that's how you'd be able to collect
now let me show you piece of code that you most likely
...most likely would do.
So, this is my empty controller.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to?
Cut-and-paste.
Code we'll talk about it and then I'll fast-forward and I'll show you what
are we collecting usually.
So, I'm replacing my.
My code and this is a very typical typical code
...me fix-all the.
Issues.
So, I'm with a help.
Visual studio I believe that.
This one.
We will be golden and then I'll describe what this code does.
So, first of all I have I decided to use
this external service that geo code my idea address you basically pass
id before as a result you get various properties
like city state so forth what you see here is the
...getting the ap address a visitor and I'm calling a very simple
Using my helper function and then I'm...
Outputting and on my page the ip address and the city
okay that's very typical straightforwardcall to external
service right and I also did here I decided to do some tracing
I wrote some tracing information so,
far you don't see any up in site in this in this code right.
Which is good?
And, another piece of code is typically fairly standardmy
sequel my sequel calls to database to thatch some data
...with some exception handling so forth so what I want to point out that
in this particular piece of code I didn't write anything specific to
up and site.
Now let's say fast-forward and we go into the cloud.
Thing what I have I have this app running
in the cloud and I want to show you what data...were able to collect.
For that particular piece of code now I've been kind of clicking on this
...yesterday so that's why you see this data here and,
what I can do is I can go into the performance and
see the performance for every page that I clicked but,
also which is very important is I was able to see all
the ...again I did not as a developer
decorate any...to the dependency and yet I was able to collect
dependency to in this particular case web service
...http call and the database we have the ability to
kind of a and automatically collect all your http
...an sql
calls both synchronous and asynchronous and associate them
with an application and with the with the function and, for example,
I can go to about function and what you see is
ic a list of executions of that of that function?
And, if I look at this request.
What you will see is that my...igni at info
Is there?
And, as a developer I just want to point out that as a developer
I did not do I did not write any line of code this is my code.
And, yet we were able to associate request
with dependency and from our experience majority of performance problems
somewhere downstream...say you're you rely on sequel and
...slow you rely on some external service and that services slow
so this would help you out of magically see all the
...problem performance problems related to dependencies.
While I'm on the code you see that there is a some piece of diagnostic code
that I wrote right line message now if I go here.
And, if I click and I
see this telemetry for this request I see there are two pieces.
And, this is very important we have the ability to do to
automatically correlate that telemetry with your logging instrumentation that request with
your logging instrumentation and what you see here is this is my request and this
is the trace that was originated from that request that's again very
importantfeature and pretty significant value that sometimes all
your logging information...the context and sometimes you have to do some strange
correlation between pieces of technology especially in big enterprise organizations
where different teams instrument and then you do your integration
and sometimes it's very hard to understand what's going on I have a...I have
...company that
with the team of hundred-fifty people created over two
thousand three hundred different tables for telemetry now imagine life site process
...you somebody woke me up in the middle-of-the-night angry to goal in search this stable and switch to another table
switch to another table what you see here is in a single place you see
all the telemetry any can slice and dice it now how can you slice and dice let's...take
I take this trace that was associate the request we've collect lots of?
...for this and, one of the properties that we've we did collect is.
The session id so what I can do
is I can click and run the diagnostic search.
For that particular session id and what you see here well this is not
...as impressive
but what you be able to see here is essentially every
interaction that particular user had during that session in that list so
you would be able to essentially mentally replay the
walk through through your site but that user did?
also I want to a point out that I don't know I've seen a lot of implementation...
custom home-grown...searching over logs.
...typically there are lots of limitations here and
there this allows you to kind of centralize all that searching
your of on top of your log so...
the idea that I mention that we would operational lice your telemetry you've already
invested a lot you thought through it we can operation lies
it making it easier and simply to support your application production.
I was going to show you
an hopefully it will work out the
...other important thing.
I was going to show you in real-life how the domain model and
for that alice and planning to use a?
Consul...
And, I will open up...consulate.
...demo consul up and we will code together.
before I do this I want to show you another way to create up and
site resource.
And, let me for that go to.
To ed experience sorry...experience.
And, I'm going to create a.
Up insight.
Sorry.
Consul up I'm creating the
I am selecting application type and this is again I want to point out
that we support multiple application we
support the server-side application...we support java
we support ios android we support it all we'll get we'll
got you covered now let me pick other because this is clearly this
consul app is not a typical application now I want to create a resource group.
So, I have lots of resource group in my a subscriptions so
...I'm going to create a new resource group.
And, I'll call it the same way the same name I'll call it the...
Which is the ultimate answer?
I will.
Ok, and, in subscription prototype so what I just did
...I created up...resource.
This bucket of telemetry and it
will be creating and pretty soon I will get
one thing that I need from that resource at this point I need and ip instrumentation
key because any piece...telemetry that I'm sending should be identified by
...while it's creating let me right some actually cut-and-paste some code.
We'll talk about the code.
So, let me add...get.
Remember all of our no, gets ...all of our is decays
a dot net is decays are...get so you can search.
And, sites.
And, you would need to get this core api remember this core api
provides the core set of.
...track request track exceptions track metric so forth.
So, I'm going to install it.
...install it and now I can again,
I can fix my usage.
I need to supporters.
I believe that I am up's thread is not.
...now as you see that
...were still missing this I keep let me get the...let me get the ip.
But, you know, what it does not matter remember we were talking about
we're talking about that I key is very arbitrary what I'm going to
do I'm going to go to my demo that I just showed you the application
up inside demo and I will grab that ip which means that I will send
my telemetry data into that into that demo that bucket?
Actually...think.
Thing now I'm thinking there's.
There was another.
Let me see for can get this...demo...
So, let me grab this I keen.
this is a...key uniquely identify piece...telemetry in the cloud
and what I'm going to do is I'm going to put this achy here?
So, now let's talk about what do I have here I have
a consul application that's in the loop asks a ask
very existential question should they use up...yes or no.
And, unless you answer yes,
exclamation point you will not leave that loop.
And, while we do that we will do couple things first of all we will time.
How much how much time do...take you to guests that a simple?
Answer that first thing and we will treat that
...will call it.
For this and that's what I'm going to demonstrate very simple thing.
Now let's run it hopes let's run it.
First answer wiring.
Any other suggestion I'm kind of maybe.
All the time ogg.
Forty-two good so we are creative let me ...out.
So, what will happen and you've seen right while we were answering
the below you've seen all those all those requests although
...all the telemetry being pumped into the cloud
ok?
And, the api is very simple it's literally I can.
She tx dot and.
This is the api track events track exception
track metric page you track trace so forth.
Ok, super simple.
Now let's take a look at hopefully the data will show up.
And, let's take a look at what we've got?
Sorry.
What you see here is a list of urls?
As you notice the way I'm using the
track request it's essentially a hacking way.
If you look at the signature it starts with
So, clearly since we were sending not a url we're sending our answers
as a url in the grid that I just showed you don't see those euros
there okay then you see the dayton
time you see the elapsed time you see the status code incorrect answer
and boolean so now if I go here this is another pretty powerful
thing what I can do I can modify this particular you
wait you why and shows something different I can show.
Requesting.
And, look, what will happen?
This is our
guys this is our data that we just sent all the cs exclamation point
...so the point I'm making here
is that api super extensible as long as you...using
our domain kind ofmodel where application accepts request
spits out exceptions and logs emit usage trace information usage
...control flow information emits metrics and rely on dependencies
you...pretty much take any applications and
use up insight to support it okay.
With no problem.
Now let me switch to the powerpoint we have fifteen minutes left.
So, just to summarize key capabilities what you've
seen we provideessentially three sixty wvu on your
applications we support multiple platforms we support devices
browsers with support servers and we put all that telemetry into
a single place so you can correlate your performance will usage data so forth.
Second since we provide a...of out-of-the-box
...collection we will correlate your logs with our...telemetry let's say
request it will help you identify and slice and dice your logs more meaningfully
in much faster we automatically collect exceptions we automatically collect the performance
...related to dependencies that significantly improve and
speedup diagnostics and user usage analysis and the last
...is you've seen how easy it was to integrate
up insight into your dot net application essentially you didn't have
to do anything to kind of fall...and
...was a check box and we've done all the our wiring
for you were doing the same thing for other platforms we have java
eclipse plug-in that allow you to do pretty much the same thing for your java
applications we have companion application for x code for android
studio so forth so you'd be able to essentially fall...and site from
...id any platform ...that you have?
We publish...as decays open-source so you guys
can see how we build those is the case.
Their on get hub you can search for application sites home and
you find are as decays
there as I mentioned we do support logging frameworks and this is the
list that we support however there are community contributions so
we have framework called sari log I didn't even know that such thing...somebody
wrote integration with sari log we have folks that wrote the integration with
end lead with slab so forth so, I would highly recommend you
to join us and together we can definitely make it better?
As I mentioned earlier we are in public preview
which means that we'll start charging you for the
for the service we support
...both free version as well as tiers of paid the version
...for the most part we believe that the free version
would cover you dev needs okay as you application mature and
grow you have a choice between basic and standard pricing
...that would allow you to essentially ...me for enough
information to cover your analytical needs okay but it's starting.
Now services in public preview we announced on wednesday.
So, you can try application...today and go to
...and sites again three things that you I want you
to remember it's a three sixty
view for your applications regardless whether you are where
...application runs...amazon google klout
...space yuan cram servers we've got you covered devices
and ios android windows phone store it's all there we provide the.
Fast and pretty powerful analytical capabilities that would
significantly simplify your troubleshooting process diagnostics
triage and detection process and.
We also provide visibility into
the usage you'd be able to see how many customers using particular particular feature of
the app we provide
pretty extensible custom the venting into api that allow you to emit
custom events and more importantly we provide metrics and those metrics are
not standard let's say pef counters that you would do that you would use or let's say
...a stats d metric that you could have used our metric
are multi-dimensional which means that you can...metric withx number of parameters
let's say five parameters and then you can slice and dice that particular metric the way you want it,
for example, you mayas one of the parameter put
...geo and this case you can slices sense standard metric
based on your geo distribution or like somebody in
the previous talk ask a question if I'm running cluster a versus cluster
...I want to see my all up performance but also I like to understand
...going on this cluster versus
glasses that cluster again you would be able to a annotate
our telemetry all telemetry that's coming from cluster a with the tag
a cluster eight and telemetry coming from cluster b with tag...
until cluster be and that you'd be able to later on not only see the
overall performance of the application across multiple plaster but also would be able to slice and
dice that performance any telemetry as a matter-of-fact by a particular stamp?
So, do you have any questions...
Sometime okay go ahead.
Yeah, so, the question is if it's.
Simple site.
Deployed in asher
let me go to simple sites deployed in measure and.
Let's say a...web apps.
And, I can see.
All my web apps.
Okay, and, I pick hopefully like this website.
What you'll see here?
Is the?
...extensions...
...going to show you the this part this is basically
a application monitoring part that would allow you to enable up and
site from the asher and the way you get this part in I remember I mention that
I will talk about gallery if you customize the blade you can
...a from the gallery any parts and if you click on the monitoring you'll
see this as if you click on the monitoring you'll see this application
...application summary part and
it just a matter of drag-and-drop.
How many of you have seen this functionality?
Have you okay some this is pretty powerful functionality and recommend you to play
with the gallery and, customize your blades because in this case
what you can do on the resource level you can pick and choose
...metrics you want to put under-resourced so you can see holistic view of
all different resources that you put in the resource group okay?
So, that the point is that you would be able to essentially.
Get to the application monitoring from here ok.
...this is basically enables...that's correct that's internal go ahead.
Okay, so, the question is was the performance impact this is a very.
Simple and yet tricky question so the way we measure performance
we measure performance in terms of degradation for art yeses so let's say
you can process with your fully pegged.
Site cpu bound
sitehundred requests per second with our monitoring our
goals are targets rtwo to enable you to process no less than
ninety nine.
So, we're not necessarily measuring cpu or a memory footprint however it is very
important but as a all up goal for us is to be less than one
percent on our ps as...in most cases you're not running your site
with hundred-percent cpu which means that in most cases you won't even notice it.
So, couple questions you showed the sequel stuff monitoring stuff.
Which...desktop output what kind of information you catch like we have problems deadlocks occasion
you get more information than just the deadlock is what's copy on that level and then
...a tech team how you limit like our tech team be able see this thank you present that session
id...the client so that when they work would call back in you could link back call to this
insight information so they could use it okay...two
...first of all when you said that there is a...
Typically deadlock happens on the deadlock on
...sql...okay deadlock on
...sql we ourselves we would not detect because we look at the
sequel as observed here so typically what happens during the
...your thread...your particular execution became a victim of a
...you've been killed on from our standpoint we would just get the exception
...we would not necessarily know what was what was going on if somebody
...match and you escalated a table...and that's why you got
curate so we won't detect we won't help you essentially
troublesome that particular thing will help you detective the same as a standard world that day there was
...problem there was an exception that will...today.
And, the other one is how to limit
emissions I would recommend limiting limit permissions using built-in feature.
...done so any blade including my let's
say my resource du-rable that's what I would that's where I would recommend this is
...resource group where I have my website and
...either website and up...component I would recommend you to use
the feature where I can essentiallyput a
...the admin rights to the resource in this case you would be able
to control who can see to...
For which app which research group so can-you display that?
That session id to the customers they...like when they
...for tech support called say I'm having problems here's my thing.
I outside this is interesting you can it would be your code because this is
our brand session id if you display that's an interesting
scenario basically display that session id somewhere in your site...when customer
...help-desk they'd be able to refer to that session id this is a pretty
cool scenario if you want...yourself you
...because now I have the reproduction that...development side close the loop and solve the
problem, yeah, but, you could display that you can access that to clients I we just have to write the...yeah,
okay, cool.
Here in the client-side.
Type of implementation like your consulate or like
...rpf app what happens in that scenario for like us
sometimes connected state like you're not always connected to add your
...so the question is essentially
disconnected scenario this is a very typical, for example, for phone could be
a and for desktop apps currently we support number of what we call channel for that
...decayed because the core the hides the complexity of follower?
...interaction with the service and one of the channel that we support is
for system channel where we willstore data locally and then we
pump it out so we do support that scenario so windows that pump out
...just visit check for...only next time ...application
...it will be first-time currently next are...of...check a...there
and...it's there it will start pumping it is there
a means to collect that data and take it like off the client in
...potentially on
...to direct where that local storage goes rather than sitting on the client
sell like to holding network share something like that we can in
...up at a different time from somewhere other than the client out-of-the-box we don't support
that functionality however in this case we can take it offline in this
case what I would do is I would just put your instrumentation somewhere like right now
you can put it locally and then offline have a little
app that read that instrumentation and basically pull are track trace...
whatever a method to pom that out but out-of-the-box we don't support the support
kind of functionality it's all we do it for ourselves but it's right now not
...okay thank you...I think typical scenario where
we put data ...in the web api to the q and then the reasons worker
role that gets from the...how would we measure and when you
tour of these and,...and processing, yeah,
this is a very...because...a scenario is if I have front-end placing some...say
...through a q and then I have a worker that we that you exacting?
...apple insight we have three different methods to measure that
Yet result basically what we're doing it it's pretty complicated and you
...to thing because in simple scenario when you actually it when it's a one-to-one when
you put one and you retrieve one but once you have more complicates
...batch it you put it then you shredded and then put in another
q it's more complicated and the way we've done it we've done it through
use of custom custer metrics where we are which you may basic
...which checking how many
...put in the q and then how many request we retrieved from the q and...and then
...graphics and if there's any difference like you eyeball it or you...
alert if there's any difference there's a problem so that's one we also
time...at least for our own implementations we time...html tree and the
at the end what we do we basically since we time step we
know start time we again emits emit custom metric that
lead drive all of our latency monitoring I suited so...heavily ourselves
we line-up inside actually monitor we heavily rely on custom instrumentation
...no like magic...so you measure it yourself and then
...of...on output site print, yeah,
we emitted as a custom metric and,
then we basically blue-like but one of
...problems we want to when you...it's completely broken it's for example,
that works but what if data...in?
...and...the problem can be they don't come
...that's why there is not...on the outside's what
...is...it ...believe me we live through this because we have
multiple regional centers then that channel data
to central location so we've lived through that I don't think that there is in reality I don't
think there's a kind of...we've got we've sold it for ourselves
through instrumentation and what we give you...give you all the means to solve
...because at the end of the day we are very
dependent on latency because an as I mentioned before performance there are
two things responsiveness for if you look at scribe type of operation...your search and
read typically...responsiveness of all the create update delete that's
your eventual consistency that's your latency measures and we are measuring
it and we've done it through through instrumentation again later talk about...visit thing it can?
So, after question the first one it's so, we have the typical website that clips and
information with from the user these type of the data than...
request a as part of the out-of-the-box of telemetry...includes
the...data what the...of what the client sending to the server to
...we don't do it ok however,
you can you're in you can do it we have again,
we kinda going deep we have a couple things we have what we called context initialize
are that would allow you to
add static tags for each request and that's typically your configurationremember
I mentioning stamp one were systems...versus we have what's called telemetry initialize
or where every time...process telemetry if you want to add some payload
...say it would automatically be edit so if you want?
By all means that this is a pi data...it's up to you
...our it's towe have a process...but...
...anytime...the send the data to...that every sequel server
...something and then come by with the resolve on does
...couple seconds to do that processing
...for the few times so thanks longer...to add telemetry from the
...today from sequel server database to know if...a process...seo
to half tennis taps to know the time between these steps between to database?
So, what you see is on
the client you see that it took two seconds and you'd like to understand what was going on
in the databases yes the question that's
a very good question and I would say in
the diagnostic scenario that's the next step when you trying to...diagnose the problem?
Currently we would not help you
with that however there are some ideas that potentially
query plan would help you understand the execution and if you see that's a bio-tech table
scan or you don't use indexes the that would, yeah,
but, it's basically taking the same information...right now from application
with applications running and then trying to start the same information of what's happening on the database
...time...and knowing what's was the work...debbie's...section of
them oman occurring users and everything so basically put it all that together,
together, yeah, because both if you running measure that's the beauty
ofessentially running measure and having a single portal what we will
do eventually is we would correlate this call?
With the...database so you'd be able to
...go back in time and while you see this particular call.
Let's say my about.
When you look at this particular call-you would be able to essentially go further and
see what was going on a sql box let's say this is my request?
A at least that's how...isthis was not
...but anyway the idea is the same basically...you can
goal further and you would seewhat was going on with the sequel if you
running everything and...that resource would be and asher and you'd be able to see currently that's
not there but this is something these are the...that we keep hearing and at some point
we'll definitely implemented and that's the value of having all your resources
kinda in address book but if they're not...it also like?
Do you...more information on pricing and in the
...yes actually it's a public on the web if
I remember correctly we have five million data points remember
that big json that you've seen is free
then we have another I think the last one is fifty million for
ninety nine dollars with some averages
and the basic I'm not sure it's like fifteen million data points
something don't hold me but it's all for twenty five twenty four dollars...but,
it's all on the web so you could you...see...you can always
...multiple of these...top which are...application noisy?
instead I would recommend each developer...and overlap...with
dual...production would have to consolidated you also have to make my.
Okay,
so, we were me this...very cool we've already made
some investments in another product that looks very similar which is new relic I don't know if
...product so if.
If you if you could compare, you know,
this to that easy equal is more powerful in some science because it's
...you're going to be correlated with the other things that are happening in
as you're like if I were to make the decision, you know,...want to switch to application
insights what would be the wvu reason for that.
Very good question so, the question was how it compares to...relic and
let me generalize it how it compares to every other atm
...out there that...a relic of dynamics dina...name
...and this is a philosophical and because in reality we all
play in the seeing in the same space however I would say that.
There is a
fundamental difference and way back when I had a company that was acquired by microsoft called
...we're doing pretty much the same thing by code instrumentation were
shelling miracles you just drop are agent and suddenly you see magic all
the years running with big enterprises I
...that it's great at a certain maturity of the project but,
as you go further this agentdoesn't give you much so what we
do we fundamentally we say that hey this is the key and it's an idea if we
can do automatic will do it so we're doing out a magic through basically
...middleware like for dot net html module
for the java that's filter for python ws gi for ruby
that's rate iraq so that's what we do but then what we're trying to do
we're trying to invest into a platform to make it easy we
trying to democratize atm so platform would emit useful
telemetry so you don't have to deploy an agent because agent means that you when you
deploy application you need to ask you ops to deploy the agent and then...that agent
attach that agent to your process right so we're trying to say
...save you from that's...now if you look at the maturity of your
application when you start you have an architect and debbie...you have to
...in the garage they have build...system they have source control defect
tracking type system and then they have their own instrumentation because that's what they do to
for day-to-day debugging once they go in
prods that's where sweet spot for tools current tools like you relic
...dynamics so forth because they want
...analytics they want to know what's going on what a customers actually came and click
the button the simplest and cheapest way to do that is to
blob java google extracts or put the ...agent but then
project mature and then suddenly you care about things called desolate,
desolate believe me I've seen all flavors and permutation what...actually
means what customer the final actually means and
...you find yourself that you writing a lot more code to
alteration allies your infrastructure and
the initial kind of return that-you got from the agent
based technology quickly diminish by the amount of custom code that you need to
...for your custom tape for your customer availability...so,
forth so I believe that this time we're trying to do something different
we trying to tell developer story
where developers are in control and I think you can use our is the key while new relic is
monitoring your site so basically by embedding our as
...key into the code and lend that code travel with the if
you will agents inside we decoupling essentially the this
step from installing the agent and we decoupling this
...from developer because you're in control ok so
that's the idea so our emphasis is on developer we do automatic as well we
have the agent also that you can go to web apiif you're familiar with like
...and download what's called status monitor and I would recommend
...download that status monitor but long-term we're trying to make sure
that the platform is in meeting a...telemetry, for example,
in the next version of...dot net all the telemetry all
the magic that I was showing right now with dependencies will be emitted by system dot
net system...data it's going to be democratize anybody can read that
it's going to be exposed as a events source?
So, that's the idea thanks very long-winded.
Height understood...session id concept you can search for all messages
within the seeing request now if we go back to that scenario where an
orders submitted and goes into a q and the network role picks it up
...do you provide any help and tracing
the messages related to that order across processes and machines would be
nicer.
As I mentioned this is something that we are looking because and,
there is there.
There's a lot of thoughts going on as we speak and, we'll see.
Okay,
so, I have to do that myself right now right now yes you have to do-it-yourself
thank you...
So, we have very lean team so on the questions I have is...around alerts
...my email alerts and what have you know, what can we do the trigger those for example,
things are up and down another thing is basically...monitoring like thresholds
...whether they build-up and napping emptied things like that just to kind of signal
wants to tell us something...wrong to some look into?
So, what you see is basically the alert the ability to add the
alert and, now you have?
Okay, you have lots of lots of metrics so.
you basically will be covered with respect to url arts and.
Processor.
There is standard
set afar custom pef counters there is a standard set of you can also
image metrics and you'll be able to raise...alert on top of that that's how I would
...lies the data and if you have q length as a metric just
will be able to capture it and...alert...thank you okay.
Ok, so, let's let me do couple thanks.
...so, I would recommend to go to our documentation and
I would recommend look, at other platforms.
That would give you a list of hopefully everything, yeah, so, that would give you a
list than if you want to understand how javascript instrumented this is the
resource that you can look up so...me see if...is a javascript so?
Well, there's this is what you would do in java.
Script.
Okay.
Basically yes I would you know,
what I would even make a point that I would run google analytics and,
up...site the same time because google analytics
typically purchase stand used by marketing folks?
And, google...more marketing kind of flavor where up
insight provides similar concept of a...that you put on a page but
we're focused on mostly kind development development time ...
so, that's google.
In many cases let's say for us
when we shipping feature there's there's a certain path that we want track?
It's interesting debate whether you don't see the conversion
because this features not...useful or the...presented is not useful or
are marketing...it's useful for developers to be able to actually
...what they want to know what type of hypothesis they want to run so that's
why we would focus would let marketing folks use g and we would
...there's another similar product but we still instrument
the our stuff with up inside because we're in control and every time we ship and we ship like
a weekly and, every spent three weeks three weeks we do
our instrumentation and we don't want to touch any of the metric that the
...marketing looks?
Question can this data be consumed by system center indeed
...currently it's not with one caveat.
If you use your system center
as a monitoring in froth for your all on prime.
And, you let's say integrate system...without with remedy as
your held desks the solution what you could do you could use
asher...measure mp pool all error lurks.
because recreate measure alerts you would be able to see those
alerts...system center an subsequently in let's say
remy ok so in that respect I would say would still
owner all the enterprise can.
Alertingscenarios but we don't
have currently anything insistence that are with that said again if you
wanted you can be you can configure continuous export.
You can configure continuous export and
pomp data out.
That's what I would that's what I would do a goal in
...click continuous...
I would pick...
...export so forth so I would basically configure continuous expert in
the blob and then do the do everything...
Okay, yeah, barely can.
So, the question is whether I can differentiate set of parameters.
Yes, and, this is a little bit deeper concept we have what we call.
Context initial laser and telemetry initialize are context initialize
...the starts once
when we initialize the context and typically you at that time
read your configuration and that telemetry will be shared across the mall
regardless then you have telemetry analyzer that we call that
called back every time when you emit new telemetry
item and add that in that inside...call back you can do pretty much whatever you want
use you can even put the runtime not only can
differentiate by different types of telemetry but you also can put some runtime earlier,
for example, if you have I don't know account id for user that's how that's
where I would put it if you have a particular user name that you web pass it through your
...that's the place where I would put it because the changes with every request?
Okay, so, the...is again it's all here.
Let me go to.
The same.
The same ui.
I would be able to.
Whatever...explore...
Metric explore and if I...chart.
I can pick the metric and.
Right now.
She discussed the metric.
So, first of all I don't know if I will see anything but first of
...all your custom metrics would be there in addition to that.
...of is nothing in addition to that
...would be able to essentially slice and dice.
Here when you...grouping.
And, you would be able to see.
Yourattribute here.
That's correct as long as long as some of the schema and we we've seen it in the schema
will do it it's a no, sequel db fuel.
It is a simple question.
Very fair question we are working on it this is this was abandoned the
clear.
For us that.
We need to.
Do something like that we have native
...android we don't have natives out native natives...if you will
with that said you still can use our...but it's a agree that it's
if it's not...will work on it?
Okay, yeah.
Okay, guys thank you and I think we.
...put evaluation forms because we.
We need to know what you think okay please.
Thanks.